{
    "id": "a76eaa112a4b4e9196c630a4a6c1ce29",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Please describe ……………….",
            "description": "We do not normally use describe with the structure indirect object + direct object.",
            "answers": [
                "your new job to us",
                "us your new job",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "90a9601ba3034f068827c1529c06386b"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would like you to explain …………………..",
            "description": "We do not normally use explain with the structure indirect object + direct object.",
            "answers": [
                "us your decision",
                "your decision to us",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e1f927f52ca2429f97e2f2ba27e54aca"
        },
        {
            "question": "Can you suggest ………………..?",
            "description": "We do not normally use suggest with the structure indirect object + direct object.",
            "answers": [
                "me a nice restaurant",
                "a nice restaurant to me"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2401df7e670441bdbfc50f6ff096ee5c"
        },
        {
            "question": "I want you ……………….. my mentor.",
            "description": "Before a noun complement ‘to be’ or ‘as’ is used.",
            "answers": [
                "to be",
                "as",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5f16abbcef044e8486790865202ce93e"
        },
        {
            "question": "We will have to wait ………………..",
            "description": "That-clauses cannot be used after wait.",
            "answers": [
                "that they arrive",
                "for them to arrive",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d5c1491b0e3a41d8b462d6b14260f397"
        },
        {
            "question": "You can’t make a …………….. pass in rugby.",
            "description": "Forward is the adjective. Forwards is an adverb.",
            "answers": [
                "forward",
                "forwards",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "52bb030e295c4a4a9d42a266d4b180fe"
        },
        {
            "question": "I look ………………. to hearing from you.",
            "description": "In figurative expressions, the form without –s is always used.",
            "answers": [
                "forward",
                "forwards",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "af10e162b4e24c7a9223f3fb8b012255"
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you want ………………. get you something to drink?",
            "description": "That-clauses are not normally used after want.",
            "answers": [
                "that I",
                "I to",
                "me to"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f8e2728e992943d7a8979507f47befa1"
        },
        {
            "question": "We drove …………………",
            "description": "\r\nHomeward and homewards can both be used as adverbs.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "homeward",
                "homewards",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f013f1f0ce1444fb863626902db401be"
        },
        {
            "question": "There is no way ……………….. that he was lying.",
            "description": "After way, we can use the infinitive or ing-form with little difference of meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "to prove",
                "of proving",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "7312261868ea4619b7d48b1e9c86be1d"
        },
        {
            "question": "Summer is ……………….",
            "description": "On the way can mean coming.",
            "answers": [
                "on the way",
                "in the way",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "a2fce29c5684439fa95fd790c064691f"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………… we go by bus or train, it will take at least 2 hours.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Whether",
                "If",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5209bcef49f74b36b3062e0e7f8ea15f"
        }
    ]
}